## PROFILE SUMMARY

Sr. Business Analyst, with **5** years' experience in **financial analysis** and **data handling** in various industries, such as **Retail Banking, Insurance, Education** and **Consulting**. Apart from being excellent **client relationship builder** and **problem-solver**, Emmi is a great team player to work with.

## **EXPERTISE**

- ✓ **Banking**, Application System
- ✓ **Insurance,** Financial Analysis
- ✓ Retail, Education
- ✓ CRM & Marketing

- ✓ Business Requirement Documentation(BRD)
- ✓ Data Cleansing, Visualization and Dashboard
- **✓** Process Automation
- ✓ Project Coordination, Client Relationship

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Business Intelligence: Advanced Excel, Google Analytics, Microsoft Power BI

Database & Platform: Cloud Snowflake Data Warehouse, Microsoft Access, Banking Application System

Related Tools: Advanced SQL, VBA/Marco, Draw.io, Jira, ServiceNow

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Wealth Operation Analyst TD Wealth, Toronto, ON

Feb 2022 - Present

Operational process

Banking

System

- Analyzed bank account transactions to ensure regulatory compliance; handle 40 customers' requests daily
- Maintained key controls & governance in line with the Bank processes to **mitigate** potential **risks**
- Possessed AP System experience using **TD Banking Systems** (WSR, RPD, WTS, SMS, EIS and ISM)
- Identified root cause of **data issues** across various platforms and analyzed **data quality integration issue**
- Assisted with **system testing** of 2 IT related projects and conducted **User Acceptance Testing** of deliveries
- Reconciled, validated account transactions and determined operational KPIs for department reporting

Financial Reporting

- Created Weekly SLA Dashboard to support Department performance evaluation and decision making
- Conducted variances/gap analysis on seasonal performance trending, Monthly workload KPIs current vs. previous and actual vs. forecasting, which largely improved reporting accuracy

#### **Data Analyst Intern**

#### **EDPYPF Services Inc., Markham, ON**

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

Dashboard & Reporting

- Improved Financial income statement report process efficiency by 80% using VBA Automation
- Gathered **business requirement** based on existing report, data investigation, user story and client meeting.
- Delivered Customer Migration Dashboard, which improved campaign target accuracy by 28%

Business Data

- Drew Process Workflow chart & optimized Process Automation for internal training purpose
- Collected and cleansed data for over 30 tables in Snowflake data warehouse for Reporting purpose
- Customer data quality control to fix duplicates, slowly changing and integration issues
- prepared project performance reports, updated project status weekly, briefed the project manager; ensured proper escalation process to mitigate project risks

### **Business Analyst**

# PICC Property and Casualty Co. Ltd., China

Aug 2020 - Sep 2021

Targeted Campaign

- Conducted market research to determine product feasibility and summarized findings into reports
   Designed Campaign Opportunity Sizing Model for marketing managers to get real time sizing estimation of targeted customers base on various business criteria selections.
- Categorized candidate by household, industry and application types, which increased response rate and reduced the direct mail cost of over 20K
- Built dynamic parameter driven financial models to predict yearly revenue & profit by insurance products
- Built templates with company's beneficial insurance products information by creating VBA/macros

Analysis & Reporting

- Created **Trend analysis** dashboard with **5 years**' history of claim and settlement using Excel
- Created Monthly Financial **Income Statements report** and conducted **cost analysis** on claims based on insurance type in geographic breakdown to help sales team better attracting prospective region clients by **20%**

# Data Analyst, Client Consultant New Oriental Vision Overseas Consulting Co Ltd., China

1107 2017 - Jul 2020

Customer Data Management

- Gathered requirements from sales team and office on site as well as finance department to improve the efficiency of the business processes and reduced cost by 25%
   Built a Microsoft Access database to integrate student and customer data that allow client to register, sign up for
- programs and track their application progress for over 2000 applicants yearly.
  Mapped and loaded data from diverse sources (Excel, Text files) into Access database; created process diagram using Windows Visio; Conducted data reconciliation and testing

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Management, Specialization in Finance | Western University, London, ON

Sep 2011 - May 2015

Diploma, Computerized & Legal Secretarial Studies | Pius Culinary & Business Centre, Montreal, QC Sep 2016 - Nov 2017 Certificate: Google Analytics - GOOGLE - June 2022 | SOL for Data Analysis - UDACITY - Sep 2021